Eion Schreiber

Web Developer

1186 Elmhurst Lane Oshkosh WI, 54904 Phone: (262) 707-9642

Email: <u>eionschreiber@gmail.com</u>
Website: <u>https://eionschreiber.github.io/</u>

CAREER SUMMARY

Scrappy Web Developer with 5 years of WordPress development experience with a knack for delivering dynamic, unique, and user-friendly solutions effectively using CSS and custom WordPress theme solutions. Expert in all areas of site creation, including design, plug-ins, and implementation. Committed to exceptional customer service at all levels of the web process, from client meetings to website maintenance after launch.

EXPERIENCE

Epic Creative, West Bend WI (Remote) - Web Developer

April 2019 - May 2022

- Build websites using WordPress, Concreate5, and other CMS systems.
- Participated in training clients on how to use their site effectively.
- Created custom WordPress themes from wireframes, Sketch files, and Photoshop files.
- Designed new features for existing websites.
- Followed ADA and WCAG guidelines when building websites.
- Collaborated with Project Managers, UX Designers, and SEO Specialists on a daily basis.
- Creating custom functionality to solve problems and speed up development time.
- Testing sites using multiple different browsers and devices and documenting errors

Destination Dino Liam, Slinger WI - Web Developer / Web Designer Intern

December 2018 - June 2019

- Participated in one on one meetings with the client using strategic questions to develop a plan for the website.
- Designed and developed the website theme from scratch, creating a branding strategy for future use within the non-profit.
- Created a system for the client to add events with ticket options for paid events they host.
- Developed a donation system so site users can donate to the non-profit using WooCommerce and PayPal.

Petco, West Bend WI - Team Lead

June 2016 - February 2019

- Managed a team of six people, helping employees with customer questions.
- Grew department sales by teaching employees about certain products.

SKILLS

- WordPress
- ACF
- Bootstrap
- CSS / SASS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Git
- HTML

- PHP
- MySQL
- Tailwind CSS
- Photoshop / Illustrator

PROJECTS

John Deere Virtual Pavilion Development

Developer for the Virtual Pavilion for John Deere website. The site showcases multiple different products in their Agricultural, Grounds Care, Sports Turf, and Golf lineups. The first rendition of this project was built so that it could integrate with the main Deere.com site using a custom framework, but then was migrated to WordPress when demands changed. I worked with many different departments and people on the project to give the John Deere team an amazing site.

Project Link: https://explore.deere.com/

Ryan Turf Website & Product Comparison Tool

Website rebuild using WordPress with a custom product comparison tool using PHP, JavaScript, Ajax, CSS, along with the Elementor page builder. Worked with the designer on multiple occasions to give the best UX design possible for the users. Worked with the SEO Manager to implement customized data to the client's CRM (Sharp Spring) for overall tracking and form management. Implemented custom Data Layer data for Google Tag Manager tracking as well.

Project Link: https://www.ryanturf.com/

Tosa Restaurant Week Site

Lead developer of the site, built using a custom child theme based on the Understrap WordPress theme. Built using PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, SASS, and HTML and created a restaurant filtering system using Ajax and PHP.

(Campaign site)

EDUCATION

Moraine Park Technical College, West Bend, WI - Web Development

2017 - 2019

Studied web development and web design using WordPress, PHP, JavaScript, and CSS.

devCodeCamp, Milwaukee, WI - Software Development Bootcamp

October 2015 - May 2016

Immersive project-based learning program designed to develop real-world software development skills based in C# and the ASP.NET framework.